I'm super excited here today to talk
about a topic that is really close to my
heart language agents I'm very excited
about this topic in the past two years
also like it's really fascinating and
I've devoted most of my time thinking
about this so I have to share some
thoughts here today right whether you
like it or not well since you in this
lecture so most likely you like it that
but you probably have heard about the
term agents a lot um many people are
super in take about it like Bill Gates B
said that it will bring about the
biggest Revolution since essentially GUI
um then Andrew n said that the agend
workflows will drive massive air
progress and then Sam timman said that
2025 is the year when agent will
work however there's definitely also a
lot of voice from the other side of the
aisle I many people think that the
current LM are just thing wrappers
around lrm agents are just thing
wrappers around LM so there is nothing
fundamental here well others think Auto
regressive LMS can never truly reason or
plan um and then um Auto gbt was one of
the early uh prototypes of these agent
systems but it didn't it was like very
popular so it's U the fastest growing
Repository in did have a history in
terms of number of stores but it didn't
take long for people to realize that it
was at at least at the time mostly more
of a prototype and there was a lot of
limitations for from a production
system if we take one step back and
think about hey what is Agents it's
really not a new thing right uh it's um
one of the very first topic we cover in
ai11 right agents and especially using
this classic schematic illustration from
Russo and noic and it has been part of
the core core pursuit of AI since the
very beginning so why all of a sudden it
became so much more popular
again so let's try to Define This Modern
agents many people hold this view that
hey you have an Dage model uh it has a
text in text out interface so the kind
of things it can do is quite a limited
it's still a lot but it's limited it's
not connected to external environment
and then once you connect that toone
environment you can perceive information
from the environment and it can exert
impact on the environment then it
becomes an
agent that that seems reasonable but at
the same time it also seems a bit
oversimplified and incomplete right we
often heard things like hey
self-reflection that that uh the an
agent or lrm looks at its own uh
reasoning process and then decide to do
autonomously decide to do something else
or like you can do multi-agent
simulation or some lot of other things
that don't necessarily involve in
external environment or at least that's
not part of the the core defining
trait fundamentally I think there are
two main competing views in the
community the dominant view I call it an
LM first view so we have first have an
LM it's amazing it's very powerful it
knows a lot of things so let's make that
into an
agent then if you take this view
naturally the implications are you think
of like building a scaffold on top of an
l and it will be a lot of prompting and
it will be heavy on engineering and I I
think that's also um a lot of the where
a lot of the sentiment that the agents
are just thing wers around L come
from I tend to take a different view I
take an agent F right so as I said AI
agent have been the core pursuit of AI
since the very beginning now this just
now they got an upgrade now we integrate
one or more LMS into this a agents so
they gain a new capability so use
language with reasoning and
communication
if you hold this view then the
implications are all the same challenges
faced by the F with a agents like how to
perceive the environments how to reason
about the environmental States how to
build World models to model the state
the uh State transition Dynamics in the
environment and how to use that for
better planning all of these challenges
still remain but we need to reexamine
them through the new dance of
LMS and also we need to tackle the new
challenges and opportunities like now we
can do synthetic data at a scale we can
do s reflection and we can also do 01
style internal
search okay if we agree on that view and
agent first view then we can look at
what's really fundamentally different
now once we're integrating uh these LMS
I think it's really the capability of
using language as a vehicle for
reasoning and
communication the power of using the
language for communication is probably
more clear um like all of us remember
the vividity the viral success of chbt
um it was the the fastest app to grow to
100 million users in human history and
um but we also know that in terms of the
fundamental capabilities trity was not
significantly better than previous
generation but open I decided to tune it
uh to be be more chatty and releas it to
the public so I think that that really
shows you the power of using language
for
communication um you get instruction
following you get in context learning
and you can easily customize the output
format but perhaps a bit more unique
this time around you know because using
language of communication we have been
doing that in decades uh in dialogue
systems but this new capability of using
language reasoning is probably a bit
more unique this time around um it used
it used to be the case that have to do a
lot of justification about why why this
is unique but now with all these new
reasoning models I think this has become
much easier um so but let's still
consider this example right most of
people would look at this example and
think gb4 was being stupid and
contradicting Itself by first thought
answer is no but there was a lot a bit
more thinking then it realize that the
answer is actually yes um but the way I
see this example it really shows the
power of using language for reasoning so
you can decide the agent the model can
decide on the fly to use adaptive the an
Adaptive amount of computes for
different problems so it got a second
chance unlike in traditional ml models
where you pay a fixed amount of computes
for any decision
right so you only have one shot and you
have to commit to
it and it's specifically in the context
of Agents reasoning is not just for the
sake of reasoning right it's not just
for math or coding reasoning is for
better acting so you can use reasoning
to infer about the environmental States
you can do self-reflection you can do
Dynamic replanning like all for the same
purpose of to for better acting better
planning in the environment
right now we're ready to reconcile this
new generation of language agents with
the previous
agents all we need to do is to add a new
type of action called reasoning by
generating tokens this in contrast with
actions in external
environments then for that we also need
to add an internal environment just like
an inner monologue where reasoning
happens
with that uh change now we can also
reconcile things like self-reflection
now it becomes just a meta reasoning
action like it's a reasoning over the
reasoning process just like meta
cognitive
functions and reason is for better
acting and at the same time due to the
power of these LMS the percept and
external action spaces are just toally
expanded as
well okay before proceed let me just
provide a little bit justification of
the use of reasoning here um because
this is such an overloaded term if we
don't properly Define it then people
will frown upon
it so um I'm sympathetic of the position
of you calling all of these as reasoning
because for people who are familiar with
like the um the due process mental model
of human cognition like by the uh famous
like late
Daniel conman in Thinking Fast and Slow
you be familiar with Concepts like hey
perception then intuitive inference and
then symbolic reasoning right the intu
of inference is fast effortless and then
symbolic reasoning is slow and
effortful but LMS they don't have all of
those
different cognitive substates for this
different type of uh Cal functions all
it has is mostly just one mechanism
which is token generation it's mostly we
will talk about this later because we
will talk about intrinsic like implicit
reasoning but mostly reasoning happens
through token generalization through
explicit language production right so if
you look at this example from G4 all
when you looks at this image its
generation incorporates all of these
different mental uh processes like what
we would call perception like what's in
it there and intuitive inference like
what you immediately infer from what you
see and also some symbolical reasoning
some more complex reasoning so I think
for this reason because uh LS really
only have this one mechanism um and that
b blend all this together so I think
it's proper to call this reasoning uh
and then one may alternatively call
these thoughts to avoid this overloaded
term but then the risk is that with
further anthrop mories these machines so
I prefer reasoning over
thoughts right another thing that I want
to get behind us before we proceed is
the name uh there are so many different
names where this agents right now there
AI agents autonomous agents LM agents
and so on so forth but I truly think
like language agents is probably the uh
most um descript uh like characteristic
name for this current generation of
Agents because the language is really
their most sedent
traits and what about multi agents well
there is perception in other modalities
and they're very important but language
is still doing the heav lifting like the
reasoning and communication
part and what about LM agents that's
probably the most popular name out there
I think what's really needed here or
characteristic of this generation of
agent
is
this capability of universal language
understanding and production which turns
out to be extremely important for agents
and but this capability doesn't have to
come from an Ln right maybe in a few
days we will go beyond LM but this need
this capability will remain so LMS could
be a means to an end in that sense is
that's as fundamental so language agents
are still a more um appropriate
name right if we take one step back and
think about the evolution of AI um I
think we're really entering a new evolu
evolutionary stage of machine
intelligence so human intelligence is
truly a model made by Nature somehow our
brain can take raw inputs from different
sensory organs and represent them in a
unified neural representation to
reconstruct the world around us and also
to support symbolic reasoning and
decision making right so that's truly
fantastic then throughout the history of
AI we have made many attempts to
approach human intelligence and manifest
machine intelligence into these AI
agents but earlier generations of AI
agents were only able to capture some
limited facets of human intelligence
like symbolic reasoning like perception
in single
modalities only recently with this
multimodal LMS and the language agent
built on top of them for the first time
we have a model that can encode
multisensor inputs into a unified new
representation that is also conducive to
symbolic reasoning and communication so
this drastically improve the
expressiveness the reasoning ability and
the adaptivity of a agent
and that's I think what makes this kind
generation of Agents so
exciting we can do a more detailed
comparison of these different
generations of Agents but for in the
interest of time I will just quickly go
through this and just focus on language
agents and the expressiveness is pretty
high for example you can compare with
the logical agents where the
expressiveness is founded by The Logical
language we use here we can the agent
the model can essentially encode almost
everything um especially the
verbalizable parts of the world but for
the non verbalizable Parts like how to
recognize a face we still have like M
model uh like inputter is to capture
those and then for reasoning now we do
language based reasoning uh instead of
like logical inferences so it's spudy uh
and it's uh flexible and it's uh
semiexplicit so it's not entirely
implicit you still have this chain of
thoughts that you can see what's going
on and fness I want to emphasize that
it's not necessarily a bad thing because
the world around us it has a lot of
fness in it um if we resort to like
something strictly very sound and very
rigid then it comes as a cost of uh
sacrificing the extractives a lot and
then the adaptivity which is a homework
of intelligence is also very high in
language agents because this a strong
prior captured by an LM and the language
use in general is very
flexible right so before we proceed let
me share with you my own concept of
framework for language agents this is
what I have been using to guide my own
research agenda in the past two years or
so um the most important things are the
what what I call Core competencies and I
to arrange them in loose hierarchy so
each box here you can roughly find the
corresponding cognitive function in a
human brain and then the bottom ones are
the more uh fundamental ones like
perception memory and embodiment and the
upper ones buil on top of the bottom
ones like planning built on top of
reasoning and World models and reasoning
buil on top of perception and memory and
so so Force we also have many cross
cutting issues like safety evaluation
synthetic data is both a challenge and
an opportunity and efficiency and many
new applications so with this framework
now you can look at any new paper about
agents and try to map it map its main
claims and uh main contributions into
this
framework all right so that's the
introduction and for the rest of the
talk we will cover try to cover three
aspects of language agents um how we
model longterm memory for which I will
use our recent work heac um then how do
these language models fully reason and I
will use our work on gra Transformer and
then finally I will talk about planning
especially World basic planning using a
word model okay so that's Sol is
memory um we'll talk about hi the main
content will be from hipac but we'll
talk about a lot of other things as well
um it's a neurobiologically inspired
lter memory mechanism for lar language
models is Le by my um student B and in
collaboration with Mii from
Stan right so if we look at how humans
or really most other animals that have a
nervous system how they learn like it's
really fascinating that that we are all
like these
247 non-stop lifelong Learners right and
all we learn is stored in our
memory so the um Eric kandall the uh
Nobel priz winner who uh got the priz
for his contribution in um in the study
of memory especially the neurobiological
foundation of memory one said that
memory is everything without it we are
nothing which I think is uh very
profound because really anything we
learn has to be encoded in our memory
and through a process called synaptic
plasticity right so basically we can
change our synapsis to capture to
memorize things and to capture all the
things we're experiencing and we're
learning and there are different ways of
uh changing the synapsis like for
example you could change the strength of
a synapsis by uh uh either adding more
receptors here U or or releasing more
like
neurotransmitters or you can do
structural changes to the synapsis um
like by growing new synapses uh for the
same uh neuron for example so this is
used more often in forming long-term
mem right so we are really 24 four seven
Learners even when we are sleeping we
are uh replaying what happens during the
day right that's what how this longterm
memory gets
Consolidated right ideally we want that
the same kind of learning capacity in
machines or especially in agents as well
because these agents they are supposed
to explore the world do things and and
then accumulate a lot of learning from
that and self-improve in some sense
right however that's very hard for the
current
Technologies um for these neuron
networks in general and lrm this
gigantic lrms in particular they are um
very they have the notorious issue of
catastrophic forgetting um so when
you're learning new things because of
this highly distributional uh
representation of these mod in these
models when you you're learning a new
things it often has unintended side
effects like some other things um like
unexpectedly got changed during that new
learning
process right and to illustrate this we
can use um and in in the lrm context we
can consider what people have doing been
doing trying to edit an LM to inject or
alter a specific effect so that's called
uh knowledge model editing right and a s
Topic in model LM model editing is the
so-called repo effects right so if you
want to change just this one fact in a
comp factual change like you want to say
hey uh the no is a citizen of Syria
instead of uh United States right and
you want you have some expected uh repo
effect
right because now the citizenship T
changed so may so he should speak Arabic
instead of English but if you actually
look at what uh what has changed after
this edit you will see that a lot of
other unexpected things have changed or
the things that should have changed but
didn't change right so if you look at
the negation of these original
statements you will see that uh it will
still predict which is wrong you want it
to the United States because of the
mutation and then there is this
um uh like the the language here also
becomes seral uh but you want it to be
Arabic and so on so forth so all of
these just tell you that because of this
uh highly distributional representation
of these artificial new networks that
makes continual learning very hard um
the human brain and animals somehow uh
figure out a way to do that but we don't
quite understand how how that happens
yet uh so cannot replicate that in
machines but that's highly desired this
kind of contining learning is highly
desired for agents and for lrms so what
can we do um a good news is that for
lrm it's possible to use an alternative
form of memory called
nonparametric memory so instead of like
CH directly changing the parameters of
an a model with the new experiences we
can just hold the new experience
external to the model so it's
nonparametric and then just retrieve
them uh using some mechanism as we
go but for that to work then of course
this is called uh rack which augmented
generation but for that to work there is
a prequisite condition right that is
when you retrieve something some
external
information and you say hey this is your
memory so you should you should take it
you should all your decision making
should be based on it then it's based on
the condition that these
lrms actually will be receptive to such
external information right um so we did
this study uh called
adaptive comedian or stub thoughts um
where we specifically study this
behavior when you have this external
evidence like from rack and then when
that directly conflict within lm's
parametrial memory what would happen
will they resist that or will they be
receptive to that um perhaps not not too
surprisingly at this point but what's
very surprising at the time is that this
LM turn out to be highly receptive to
external evidence even when that
conflict with their parametri memory so
for the two examples here you have a
question and the ground truth answer in
this case the parametric memory of the
LM is correct but if you give it a
coherent counter memory like this then
Ln will happily accept this and change
it answer and in this case the parimal
memory was wrong and you can correct
that by giving is the correct content
memory but that kind of paves the way
for non-parametric memory for LMS
because of their um being highly
receptive to this external evidence of
course this has other implications like
safety like maybe this that this means
that these LMS could be highly Gable but
that's not uh that's not the focus
today okay right now let's talk about
how to really make longterm memory work
for
LMS most people know that rag is the
defao solution today right you uh given
something that is for example the the LM
doesn't know or uh Beyond its knowledge
cut off dat then it will retrieve from
the internet and then user retrieve the
information as a kind of longterm memory
uh to uh answer the
question but if you think about how R
works okay you embed this evidence uh
into vectors then you do Vector based
similarity to retrieve them that seems
far
simpler uh far less sophisticated than
the human memory system where we can
recognize patterns uh in massive data ma
raw experiences we can create a lot of
associations of cross them and we can
dynamically retrieve them uh to to for
the current context and so on so forth
so to illustrate some of the limitations
of the current in backing based R system
let's consider this
example let's say you have a query uh
which is Stanford Professor works on the
Neuroscience of Alzheimer's so you have
two stting concepts Stanford and
Alzheimer's then let's assume just
hypothetically you have a bunch of
passages if each passage only contains
part of the information so you don't
happen to have a passage that tells you
uh like this person is both a stample
professor and works on Alzheimer instead
what you have is this separate passages
okay this passage says this person works
at Stamper this passage says that this
person works on Alzheimer and then you
will see like there is one person who
works at
and on alimer but it's in separate
documents you don't happen to have one
document that tells you all right so
what would happen if you just use
embeding B
rout now you Ed each of these passages
into a vector you embed your query into
a vector you do compare the similarities
one by one then you will find all of
these passages are equally likely
because each of them captures precisely
50% of the information right and as a
result the model has to manually go
through all of these passages to figure
out uh which ones are the correct
ones right and you can imagine there
could be thousands of professors working
at stur and even more people working on
asers right so it's a one to many many
to one
relationship but our human memory
doesn't work that way somehow when if we
have come across like this like this
person works on Alzheimer's this person
also works at Stanford then we will
build some sort of Association among
them such that when this query comes we
can very easily and quickly find that
hey this person is connected with both
Stanford and isms so it's the answer we
don't have to go through recall all of
these other information to derive at
that uh
conclusion right so in that sense ining
based R works very differently from
Human
memory now to study how this exactly how
the human Works in this regards so we
turn to this wellestablished theory of
human L memory called the hipocampo
indexing Theory it basically goes like
this I I'll summarize it in an overly
simplified way um it says that your raw
memory is Sor on your near cortex
particularly uh like the in where the
memory was first generated right so when
episodi memory like the auditory part of
it will be stored in auditory cortex the
V qual will be stored in the v cortex
and so on so forth that's why when you
are trying to record something you were
like relieving the moment like um
because it's just re triggering the same
neurons as if you were perceiving them
right but importantly you also have an
structured index stored in the
hippocampus that creates a much closer
much uh essentially shortcuts that
associate all these disparate memory
units together right um and that's what
we are trying to mimic
here this kind of separation and
structure index give you two important
uh faculties of human memory it allows
you to do pattern separation so you can
differentiate memories in very funu way
certainly Beyond just vectors at least
at the concepts level right if you think
about your episodi memory the second
second and the second before they are
very similar to each other how can you
differentiate the differences that
requires a very fying gr separation of
patterns um but more importantly which
is more relevant here is pattern
completion right we can in recover
complete memories uh using just partial
cues like the previous example the
partial cues are Stanford and isers and
then you can quickly recall this whole
uh fact that this person is associated
with both of them and that's due to this
um structure index in a hioc
campus right so that's what we're trying
to mimic in h hippo we're trying to
build a similar structured index for rec
systems to enjoy some of the same
benefits of the human launter memory
system um I won't get into too much
details so just like at a high level um
but this in the hipocampo indexing
Theory there are three main parts right
there there is the ne cortex and hpoc
campus and then there is the Paro
regions that connect the two so the H
the new cortex is more about uh pattern
separation so you will process the raw
experience extract patterns out of this
concept and so on so forth and then then
the hioc campus is more like the
structure index so it's the indexing
Auto Association and then theoc campus
regions is more like the the working
memory that connects to then do some
more uh um like iterative thinking
around
there so to mimic this process um we
have two spaces we have the offline
indexing phase and the online F phase
for offline indexing I say you have
these passages as inputs we use an LM to
serve as a new cortex that will do open
information extraction to extract these
tripletes like the concepts non phrases
and their relationships like the verb
phrases so extract this uh triplets then
we do try to build a Knowledge Graph
particularly this a this is a schema
that's Knowledge Graph so we don't have
a ology or the predefined schema or
anything like that everything is
extracted by an LM from the raw
experiences right so we built a n graph
by uh consolidating all this uh new
extracted Concepts and phrases as nodes
and edges that's the offline indexing
phas and this becomes our artificial uh
hipocampal
index then the the this we use an dense
retriever here as an encoder to
consolidate things like to identify like
which concepts are uh similar to other
or synonymous to each
other then in the online retrieval phase
when a query comes in like the Stanford
as example then we'll identify the
concept we use named entty recognition
so now we got Stanford and isomers we
still use a dance uh
to find the similar nodes in my
Index right and then those noes become
the C the noes for the graph search
process so we will use this as seed to
do a search process on the graph to uh
to find like the most related things
right and this particular Graph Search
algorithm we're using here is
personalized the page rank
okay so for people who don't quite
remember what a personalized P brand uh
Works um I I'll do a quick recap right
so it's a random work process on the
graph where you start with some C the
notes so those start with probability uh
one then you use a random walks uh
stting from the C not to disperse the
probability Mass to their neighboring
notes so the nodes that are closer to
this C no or like especially those are
in intersection of multiple C the nodes
will naturally end up with a higher
weights then in this case Professor
Thomas who is connected to both Stanford
and RM will naturally stand out and
getting the highest weights now we can
use these weights over concept to
reweight the original passages then to
retrieve the most uh highly weighted
passage right so that's how people rap
Works in a nutshell of course there are
a lot of details that we're not covering
but this is the main
chest and it turns out like some simple
uh strategy like this uh biologically uh
fible strategy works also extremely well
in practice right it's not enough I
think it is of course a neat idea like
hey this is biologically inspired uh how
cool is that but I think it's equally
important for it to actually work to
work very well and better than existing
Solutions in practice and that's what we
showed with hippach so compare hippach
with the state of the art Dan retrievers
uh at the time and show that on multip
uh QA data sets three standard mop QA
data sets uh is much uh it performs much
better uh by Marin and also you can you
can compare Hipp with this iterative
retrieval methes like
IRC and it also works better than this
iterative method and also because H the
nature of it really this structured
index and the graph search though it can
it's highly complimentary to all these
existing methes you can easily integrate
it with other methes like IRC and then
you get a big boost as
well okay and to better understand where
does this power of Hippo comes from we
can consider a type of questions what we
call Path finding questions like the
example running example we have been
working with so if you think about the
in this information space like the this
huge graph of everything connected to
everything what's the solution path um
of structure for this question looks
like you will see it's like uh it's not
just like a one to one to one kind of
path it first has start with a one to
many religion like Stanford there are
many professors working at Stanford then
among those is our answer Professor
Thomas and uh from this and then for the
people to seares to alzheimer's that's
also a many to one relationship so there
are many people working on Alzheimer if
you don't have like PRI knowledge about
your the answer you're looking for then
naturally you'd have to search through
all this um hundreds of thousands of
candidates for you to find uh Professor
Thomas and hipak by explicitly building
extracting and building these
associations from the raw uh inputs that
allows you to kind of create this
shortcut to quickly find the true answer
well if you use cober or like I then
they won't be able to find it
efficiently okay so that that was hio um
that was published in neurops which is
just two months ago but it in today's
pace is still like ages ago um so as a
um I'm very excited to share that hipak
V2 is coming very soon and um so a
problem with hipak or all these recent
structured augmented rack message like
graph rack light rack Raptor and so on
so for the if you so the compare favor
body with to this like uh simpler
baselines like this small dense
retrievers like Cobra V2 or cont
but recently there have been many large
embedding models like a g like a m BS
and if you actually compare this
structured augmented rack method with d
you will see that they are much worse
including Hipp rack um they are working
compare compare okay on this multihop QA
husks because they they they were mostly
uh designed for these kind of tasks but
if you just look at all other scenarios
like just some very simple QA or some
discourse understanding and so on so
forth like they don't work that well so
as a result it's very hard for this
message to become just a dropping
replacement of uh like inag based
message then in hpor V2 we did a bunch
of clever uh upgrades to hia V1 and the
result is that now V2 is comparable or
than the best loging Bing models across
the board so then it's much more
plausible to just use g r V2 as a
dropping placement uh replacement for
your rag
system we hope to release this uh very
soon right so for memory part the
takeaways um so memory is really Central
to human learning um and long-term
memory through parametric Contin
learning for LMS is very hard but
fortunately non-parametric memory like
rack could be a promising solution but
and the reason trending in rag is to add
more structures to embeddings like hi
rag or graph rag to enhance like the
sense making capability of these models
like the ability to integrate larger
more complex and uncertain contacts and
the associativity of this memory like
the capacity to draw for multiple
connections between this parot pieces of
information okay so that's memory and I
think we're still quite far away from uh
developing a very sophisticated memory
system uh but we are on well getting
there um there are still many gaps like
how to handle like episodia memory like
the spal temporal aspects of things
which is Central to human memory uh
don't have a good solution yet hey so
memory is the most fundamental aspects
in my opinion um then uh let's get back
to get to another very fundamental
aspect which can be can be built on top
of re memory which is
reasoning and our discussion today will
be mainly based on this paper gring of
implicity relations in Transformers uh
is that by um the student from our group
b one and it's published in neops this
year last
year right so we will be talking about
implicit reasoning um in implicit
reasoning we don't do chain of thoughts
so there is no verbalized chain of
thoughts explicitly we ask the LM to
directly predict the answer like in this
example of compositional reasoning you
let's say the language the langage model
has memorized or know these two Atomic
facts that Bar's wife is Michelle and
Michelle was born in
1964 then the model will be given this
input like bar wife born in and is asked
to directly predict the answer 1964 in
this compositional reasoning fashion
right um so if you do change of thoughts
of course you can try to recall head the
Bark's wife is Michelle Michelle was
born in this so therefore Dan is this
but we want to push the model to
implicitly just using his parameters in
a single forward PA to do this
reasoning why like C like especially
this long C is all the rage right now
like in R1 or o1 then why why does
implicit reasoning mat um that's this is
also what I would means uh in the
beginning like why this um the reasoning
mechanism of these LM is mostly just uh
token generation but implicit reasoning
is still part of the reasoning
repertoar um so why does implicit
reasoning matter first of all this is
the default mode of training or
pre-training because during training
time when the model is asked to predict
the next token with cross ENT loss
there's no coot right at least not for
now so in training time model has to
compress the data has to do inut
reasoning in order to uh reasonbly
predict the next token so no matter what
I think it's important to understand the
implicit reasoning capability of langage
models also that increas reasoning
fundamentally determines how well this
models acquire structure representations
of the facts and the rules from their
training data um and
finally like there's a lot of uh
speculation about how this this o1 or R1
style long coot emerge from a um I think
one possible hypothesis as it is in my
mind is like this like you start with a
capable base model right if the base
model is not capable enough then I won't
do much so you start with a capable
based model like DC V3 and it probably
has already learned all of these basic
constructs or strategies for reasoning
right so like self-reflection like
analogical reasoning and so on so forth
then and maybe in an implicit reasoning
fashion like just some kind of reasoning
circuits in the
parameters then reinforcement learning
with this verifiable rewards is just to
incentivize the model to learn to use
the right combination of strategies but
it's not learning new reasoning
strategies through I and then it also
encourages the model to keep trying
don't be lazy right so if we uh if this
hypothesis is true then understand how
these models how these re different
reasoning strategies work within the
model becomes even more
important right
um so back to inut reasoning um before
our work there were a bunch of work a
great work that shows that LMS truly
struggle with implicit reasoning I some
people show that it struggles with
compositional reasoning like this uh
there is a famous compositionality Gap
and then some other people show that LM
even like G4 at the time strugle was
simple things like comparative reasoning
or comparison like Trump is 78 Biden is
82 then Trump is younger or older than
Biden
so that was like the the uh previous
conclusions but we have we had different
opinions um it seems to us like these
all like kind of um contribute to like
this autor regressive lrms and never
truly reason or plan kind of narrative
um but we had uh some different belief
we have more faith more confidence in
language models and Transformers so we
we want to more carefully study uh this
um problem then to see whether we can
get some new insights so we started with
this research questions first can
Transformers learn to reason implicitly
or are there fundament limitations that
prohibit robust acquisition of this
skill and then what factors like is that
the scale of the train data the
distribution of the train data or the
model architecture that control the
acquisition of implicit implicit
reasoning okay so with these two
questions let's discuss the
setup the model and optimization are
pretty standard but we want to um I
don't want to introduce questions here
so it's just like a standard decoder
only Transformer intive 2 architecture
and we also show that the results are
pretty robust to different model skills
so you can have a deeper model but the
conclusions are the same then the
authorization is also pretty
standard then for the data will be using
will be synthetic data because we want
to carefully control all the factors uh
in this investigation so that we can
separate out the uh the problem we want
to
study so you can imagine like let's just
consider composition we study both
composition and comparison but let's
focus on composition for now the data
will look like just a random n graph it
has each s of entities and our relations
we set R to 200 um so then it's a bunch
of nodes and then this different ration
C
then it has these are the atomic facts
right like uh Superstition the scener is
Ste and then we can use this Atomic fact
to get some infert facts or this two
half compositions following the
composition rule like if the head entity
R1 Bri entity and then Bridge entity r
two tail entity then we have this
composition effect like head entity R1
R2 T entity so it's
like bar um wife uh born in
1964 right so this composition and you
can think uh like comparison the data
for comparison is
similar okay then the important setup
here is that we want to study inductive
learning of deduction rules right um a
fancy phrase but let me just decompose
this for
you first of all we want the model which
is the the decoder only Transformer to
learn inductively so just give a bunch
of training examples you want it to
learn these rules and particularly these
are deduction rules so um this is a
typical deduction rule right you start
from some premises and then you uh can
deduce a new fact right so this is
inductive learning of deduction rules
then um there are
two generalization settings what I would
call the in distribution setting and the
out of distribution setting or this
setting can also be called systematic
generalization so it goes like this for
the atomic facts like those edges in the
N graph we split it into two sets the ID
set and the O set then they all go
through the same rule like the
composition rule you get the
corresponding infert facts right then
for this set of infer facts from the ID
Atomic facts we split into two sets the
training uh uh the training set and the
te ID test set right so this for this
infer
facts um but in the ID test sets even
though we have not seen this exact infer
fact in our training data so it's an
unseen infer fact but we have seen all
of its constitutes like those atomic
effects being composed in with other
Atomic effects in this ID training sets
right I know it's a it's a bit of
mouthful but just bear with me so for
any of these infert fact in the ID test
set like um Barack uh wife born in
1964 maybe you have you have not seen
that exact in fact in your training data
but you have seen like for example the
relation um like bar wife Michelle you
have seen this Atomic facts being
composed with other relations also
similarly you have seen the other uh
Atomic facts like Michelle born in 1964
being composed with other Atomic facts
you just haven't happened to see that
exact INF fact like bar uh wife born in
1964 so that so that you still need some
generalization to capture
them but for the O test set then you
still have seen all of the atomic
effects because otherwise the model
doesn't know that this Atomic these
Factor exist um but you have never seen
any any of those atomic facts uh being
composed in a compositional fashion like
being composed with other relations
right so that's in that sense it's a
stronger generalization setting so
that's why it's called a systematic
generalization if the a model can do
this then essentially it means that the
model has truly learned this rule this
deduction rule so that you can just
apply it to any arbitrary new facts
right um so that's really the goal for
uh this uh learning of detection
rules now with all this lengthy setup in
mind let's look at some fun Parts look
at some interesting takeaways from our
investigation the first surprising
conclusion we found is that Transformers
can learn to reason implicitly but only
through a process called
gring what is gring
um so let's look at the this uh figure
for now this curve is the training
accuracy you can see it quickly goes to
100% that means uh the model the
training has overfit at these points but
if you look at the T the ID test curve
right when the model first overfits here
the test accuracy was still very
low and if you keep training the model
Way Beyond um like the saturation or
overfitting like the overfitting happens
around like 10,000 steps and if you
train it like uh two 20 times more
optimization steps like to to these
points this is log scale for example
like keep in mind then all of a sudden
um generalization happens right this at
least the ID generalization happens
right so the model gets to 100% test
accuracy on composition in the ID
split similarly for
comparison the overfeeding happens very
early on but it takes about 20 more
times um of train optimization steps for
generalization to happen and
interestingly for comparison all the
test accuracy also get to 100% so that's
a problem we're looking into
dat right um so that's quite interesting
right this Transformers three can learn
to reason implicitly but only through
rocking and it's one of the first
studies that establishes this connection
between rocking and implicit reasoning I
believe and we will uh investigate why
that happens in a
second another take immediate takeaway
here is that as we just said that the
level of
systemicity of generalization varies by
the reason type for compositional
reasoning there is NE it never managed
to learn to generalize o well for
comparative reasoning uh o
generalization did happen so we want to
understand why there is such a
difference as
well then another in interesting
takeaway here is that
so before this study there were already
some studies that look at graphing and
then I'll try to understand why gring
happens and under what conditions would
uh gring happen then one common belief
in the literature was that there is a
critical data size like once your your
total amount of data surpasses a certain
threshold then graphing happens
otherwise it won't happen but in our
study we try to study this uh this
hypothesis very carefully then we find
that actually it's not the data size but
the data distribution that matters so in
this experiments on the rights we um we
keep the the so there is two F two
variables there is the total data size
which is controlled by the number of
entities and it's proportional to the
total data number of training examples
and then there is um by which is the
ratio of infert versus um Atomic facts
right so if this number is larger that
means that you have more infer facts
than uh then you have Atomic effects
right so on the right we keep the ratio
fixed and increase the number of
entities or the total data size then you
will see the speed of generalization is
roughly the same when you increase the
total data
size right um it's more or less the same
however when you keep the uh data size
fixed so it's the same number of
entities um you just change the ratio
five like from 3.6 to
18 then you see the speed of
generalization um
strongly positively correlates with this
ratio if you have a higher ratio then
the generalization will happen uh faster
and at some points it will be as fast as
uh the overfeeding of the training
data right so this really shows that
it's the critical data distribution that
matters not the sheer size of your
training
data with all those take interesting
takeaways um I would job is not done
here yet because there are still some
very important questions we have not
answered right so why does grocking
happen what exactly happens during this
long grocking process what's going on
with in the within the model and why
does the level of systematicity in
generalization vary by the reasoning
type so all of these questions require a
deeper look inside the model
that's the mechanistic interpretation
part of this
study so we will use some uh popular and
now this very standard uh mechanistic
interpretation tools one is uh logic
lens so here we apply the internal
States at uh some uh position in within
the Transformer uh and multiply it with
the output embedding Matrix so that we
can get a distribution over with output
of vocabulary so we kind of get a peak
into what this internal representation
uh is about right then we we will also
use so-called costal tracing
um like in a nutshell this allows you
this technique allows you to
um measure quantitatively measure the
amount of impact of a certain internal
state to um the
output right so it's a it ranges from
zero to one if it's closer to one that
means that this position uh this
internal state has a larger impact on
the final decision right I won't get
into the the very details because that
that will take too much
time um so with this uh mechanistic
interpretation technique
now we can try to find or discover
rather that um the corresponding
generalizing circuit formed for
different reason types then this is what
we found uh very very beautiful we find
that for
composition after gring the Transformer
will learn a generalizing circuit like
this it's a kind of stage circuit right
so this is the input to Transformer you
have the head entity R1 and R2 and then
this is layer Z layer zero this is layer
eight the final layer um then the first
few layers of the Transformer will
essentially do two
things for these parts it will process
the first hop essentially so look at H
and R1 and then find the bridge entity B
here we're using logical Dan here um
so it has memorized this Atomic fact in
the first few layers to the extent that
it can reliably predict B at the year
five
then the another thing that needs to be
done here is that it needs to defer the
processing of R2 so you cannot forget
about R2 because R2 needs to be used L
even though it doesn't need to use R2 in
the earlier day
it needs to use R2 when it has found B
the bridge entity okay so once the
bridge entity is identified is then in
in the internal States then it can be
combined with R2 and then it has
memorized the atomic fact that b R2 is T
so then you can combine the bridge
entity B and the delay the processing R2
to predict t right so that's the
generalizing circuit for composition it
has two clear stages and that will also
determine its generalization behavior
that will analyze
later well on the other hand the
comparison relationship or reasoning has
a different circuit what we call a
parallel circuit remember for comparison
it's like you have two entities E1 and
E2 you have you know some value of some
attributes of this entity like this is
uh um Trump this is Trump this is Biden
and then Trump is V1 is 78 Biden is 82
then the prediction is uh who is older
is like Trump is younger or um older or
equals um than uh Biden right then the
circuit here is more of a parallel CC
okay so the first few layers of the
Transformer were learn to in parallel
retrieve the attribute values like 78
and
82 then the uper dat years we'll use
this retrieved values to do the
comparison and then to predict um the
final answer whether is smaller than
equal or
larer okay so different the reason
through mechanic interpretation we can
find the generalizing circuit
configuration of different reason types
and they are indeed different and this
different configuration will determine
their level of systematicity of
generalization but before that um let me
share like a simple way to fix or to
improve this uh systematic
generalization uh especially for for
composition right um so as we showed
earlier for composition o generalization
never happened um why if you think look
at this circuit and think about it that
becomes kind of uh um off ofus right so
for the O generalization to
happen the model needs to do a few
things it needs to First memorize a copy
of the first half Atomic effects like H
r1b in the lower lers of the transform
right so that you can find the bridge
entity at the ler five then it also
needs to store a copy of the second hop
Atomic effect but in the
operaters right because the second hop
has a delayed the processing so it needs
to somehow store effect the atomic
effect B r2t here not in the lower layer
but in the upper
layer however for the old generalization
remember our definition of l is that
none of these Atomic facts has been seen
during training to be composed with
other
facts in that situation the model has no
incentive to store this second H Atomic
fact in the oper
layers it only seen this uh fact Atomic
effect individually so it it can easily
memorize them in the lower L years but
it doesn't have the in incentive to
store another copy in The Operators
because that requires actual effort
that's why all de generalization of
composition never happens well for
comparison you don't have this stage
processing so you only need to store one
copy of the atomic effects and you can
retrieve that the value in the uh lower
day years here for the comparison so you
don't have that issue and that's why o
generalization of comparison does happen
okay if and to further validate this
hypotheses we can do a we did an
intervention here so if that is inde the
case that is because the model doesn't
have incentive to store the this Atomic
effect in oper layers then we just need
to do some parameter sharing some cross
year prish sharing so you kind of tie
the weights of the lower layers with the
weights of the upper layer so it's a
parameter sharing and then if the lower
layer has memorized an atomic effects
then the uper ler will get a copy of it
as well so we did that intervention and
turns out boom all de generalization
start to happen for composition right so
this further validates the hypothesis
it's a bit dense but I think that this
is probably one of the most interesting
slides of this uh or analysis of this
work
um
so remember we um try to do or try to
understand what exactly is going on
during gring we said that the gring
process is when this um like this
generalizing circuit start to form but
in what exact way that's still unclear
so through um like costal tracing we can
actually identify like what exactly is
going on during
rocking
um let's
first
um let's first focus
on this
speaker
um or let me first say this so we
believe bling is the phase transition
from root learning to
generalization
so
brocking starts when the model has
overfit the train data right so but in
that Pro in at that point the model has
only done root uh root learning so it
just BR forcely memorized all the
training data including the infer facts
but not actually in a generalizable way
but the train because it has memorized
all of them so the training loss will be
zero right um but it doesn't mean that
it has capture this generalizing circuit
then the blocking process is essentially
the F transition from the initial Road
learning to the generalization is where
this generalizing circuit gets formed
and now let's analyze like how exactly
it gets formed um the first thing we
will look at is this
figure right we look at uh two things so
S5
R1 is this
position right so this is the fifth this
is s stands for state so this is a state
of dayer five as the position of R1 so
it's this one S5
R1 then we can use logic dance to decode
what's captured in that um state
representation in that state you can see
the grocking
process and similarly we can do that for
s five R2 so this
position so once brocking
starts the model already has and this is
mrr so is the main re reciprocal r but
basically it just tells you like the
like this bridge ENB the ranking of the
bridge ENB in the logic logic
L if it's one it means that the state
here will all always predict the bridge
entity B uh so that means that it has
encoded this information so when the
gring starts B is already there the m
equals one so that means this state here
always predict the bridge and B which is
what we want right we want the first H
to get us the bridge entity that is
great but remember we also need the
model to do a delayed processing of R2
so that at this point you can combine B
and R2 to predict the tail an the
T but if you look at mrr of R2 at this
uh
position when brocking
starts it does not have R2 there so it
has a b here but it doesn't have R2
here despite that the model has a train
so this is on the training set so the
model has a training loss of one of zero
so the model has can perfectly predict
the tail and the T despite not using R2
here uh to combine with B that means the
model is just doing root um learning so
you just learn memorize that Hey
whenever I see HED R1 or R2 then I will
predict t but it's not actually using
doing this stage thing like getting the
bridge entity and then combine with R2
to get another use another Atomic fact
and do the
reasoning but through the grocking
process you can see R2 gradually
increases so at the end of a gring it
always predicts R2 then you have B here
you have R2 here then you can actually
do uh recall the atomic effect here to
predict the
TT so this is further
corated by the cost of tracing results
here so remember through Cal tracing we
can quantify the Cal strength of each
state to the final prediction and this
is the um caal strength of each state at
the beginning of gring and this is of
gring then we can do we can calculate
the difference between the two and find
their
diff you can see the diff mainly happens
here at uh S5
R1 so that means in the beginning of GRA
roing even though the model has be has
the bridge entity B here it does not use
it right he just do did a road learning
so it directly predict the tail entity
but the grocking process is the process
of the model learning to use this bridge
entity property so giving it a stronger
caal strength to the final prediction
and this combined with the fact that the
um we just shown that through logic Den
that R2 the groing process is where this
R2 start to emerge right this combines
give us um validates the hypothesis that
um now this gring process is really the
process of forming this generalizing
circuit that this stage stage circuit
that we just shown for
composition and we can actually explain
uh even though not we didn't do any
proof of any sort but you can roughly
understand why this kind of gring
Behavior happens through the circuit
deficiency and the
regularization um the generalizing
circuit is much more efficient than the
memorizing circuit the circuit for root
learning um so and because you also have
regularization right the L2
regularization term for example then if
you just keep training even after
overfitting the regularization term will
decrease and then we'll gradually favor
the circuit with higher efficiency which
is the generalizing circuit so that's
why you find this still beneficial to
claim way over Beyond overfitting
because that's when the regularization
start to kick in and gets you the more
efficient
circuit but I think at least let me give
you the definition of planning because
that's in itself is a very confusing
thing for various reasons um so in the
context language agents who will work
with this simplified definition of
planning given a go g decides on a
sequence of actions a z to a n that will
lead to a state that will pass the go
test uh gen right so of course this is
over simplified because we don't talk
about the state space the observation
Spa uh space and then the actions have
they are not just Atomic actions they
have prec conditions uh that have to be
met before they can be taken and so on
so forth but for this um purpose I think
that it's enough to have this definition
then um with this definition we can
analyze this General Trends in planning
settings for language agents compared
with the classic planning setting which
has been studied in for decades um
generally I think the
expressiveness in goal specification is
drastically increasing so now can can
express our goal in natural language as
opposed to some formal language which is
usually much more limited in
expressiveness and also we have a
substantially expanded or open-ended
action space um so instead of like some
their constraint action space like hey
you have a robot you can move forward
you can turn left and so on so forth now
you can you have an even open-ended
action space and we will see some
examples soon
later then and because of those it
becomes increasing hard to do automated
go test um imagine you have a web agent
that is just doing things on the web
then a lot of the time you just simply
cannot just write a go test beforehand
like what what the go state will be
like but that's fine uh because fness is
really a inherent part of this world
I'll skip this one um so I just give
some examples like uh for web agents um
like from our M web you'll
see like in terms of the task uh the
goal specification right the uh user can
say ask for anything on an opal websites
um so it's very broad um and in natur
language and then in terms of the action
space right yeah you have some broad
actions like types like you can type you
can click you can drag you can hover on
some elements but the actual actions
like what elements you click on these
actual actions are
dynamically
populated on each web page so if you go
to a different web page your action
space will be different right so and
it's a very big action space you have to
discover on the Fly and of course the go
test is also very hard but um
and then there's another example of
travel planning that has some similar
characteristics but we will skip here um
so the I think these are some the of the
general trends for language agent
planning and that these are I think
these are good Trends yeah it makes
things more challenging but for for the
batter because it now we can support
much more realistic and useful
application scenarios um with these Dage
agents so let's see what what can want
to talk about this um maybe very quickly
um but for people who are interested in
web agents or computer us agents I
encourage you to look at this series of
work like M web the first hour based web
agents and then CX where we first
introduce a visual perception into web
agents and then ound that where for the
first time we make a human like
embodiment for computer use agents so it
only perceiv environment visually
there's no HTML or anything like that
and then you directly do pixel level
operations on the screen um and that's
um that this minimal this design
actually works the best across the board
and then we will talk about web dreamer
which is model basic planning for web
agents okay so let's consider the
different planning paradigms for
language agents the most common one is
reactive planning or react right imagine
each note here is a web page then at
each state you have several candidate
actions you can take that will result in
a different state for reactive planning
you just at each state observe the
environment reason about it then make a
decision and commit to the decision and
then that gets you to another state then
you just keep doing this right so it's
fast it's easy to implement but the
downside is that it's great and it's
sting so you often find yourself stuck
in some bad State and there's no way
out then naturally when talk about
planning we just think about search or
tree search um so you for Tre search
compare with reactive planning you can
do backtracking you maintain a value uh
assignment for the states on your search
Frontier then you explore the most
promising uh Branch at some points if
you find that not promising you can
backtrack and then to find to explore
another Branch right so that gives you
more systematic
exploration but the downside here is
that it's in real world environments
like the internet um there are a lot of
irreversible actions that makes
backtracking impossible or as is very
hard and then it a lot of this
exploration could also be unsafe or slow
to just show you how P pervasive this
state changing and irreversible actions
are in real world environments let's
consider just amazon.com right on these
single websites you can have men dozens
if not hundreds of these State changing
actions like you can place an order you
can uh make a return you can create an
account that you will agree to the terms
and use and then that that has legal
implications you can change your privacy
settings and so on so forth right if it
it's there is no like this Universal
magical uh undo button that you can just
try bunch of things and then magically
undo and then go back to the uh initial
States um so that makes treech in real
world environments hard uh and then
there's also the safety and costly
issues so ideally we want to do model
based
planning imagine you have a word model
that that at each stat it can you can
trigger the world model to simulate the
outcome of each candidate
action then that gives you a chance to
um to evaluate the long-term value and
safety of each candidate action before
you have to commit to it right then you
find the most promising candidate action
through simulation then you commit to it
take it uh assuming it to safe and then
you get to another state then given to
this all over
again right so it's faster and safer
compared with Tre search and you can
also do still do systematic exploration
but the downside is really how to get
this magical world
model let's start with what is a world
model uh because this is another
overloaded term for our purpose here
we'll take this definition is a
computation model of environment
transition Dynamics so basically if I do
this right now what would happen next
right very
simple then if it's that simple and so
good what hasn't been done for language
agents
yet well the issue here is
that if you think about world models in
the classic uh deep learning literature
that that's usually started in
reinforcement learning right e that
where you have these simple simulated
environments that you can do millions of
times of uh trials and then you you can
use that to learn a world model for that
simple
environment what we're dealing with here
is much more complicated even just for a
single website right there could be
hundreds of different web pages on a
single web page there could be hundreds
of different actions and they can be
constantly changing uh because the
backhand database is changing
and then this complexity quickly
compounds if you consider that there are
billions of other websites out there
right in that sense we need a kind of
generalist word model for the internet U
that seems very
hard fortunately we find that LMS can
actually reasonably predict these State
transitions so in this example if you
ask an nowm if I click this icon what
would happen then you can recog that hey
this is a shirt uh then this probably a
product so the next stage will probably
be about some product details and
because it's a shirt so there will be
sizing options and other things right
because LM have this word knowledge
commense knowledge is trained on the
internet so it can uh do a reasonable
job far from perfect but
reasonable so we web dreamer leverages
exactly that we stimulate a world model
for the internet using an LM in this
case gbt 4 um then when you have you're
at a state you have a few candidate
actions you can use the world model to
simulate the outcome of each candidate
action you can even do multi-step
simulation you have another value
function which is also simulated by RM
to tell you how much progress you would
have made going down that path and then
you can choose the uh the highest valued
action you take that action get to the
next state and then do this all over
again right so that's model basic
planning for web agents it's far from
perfect but it's um it's a reasonable
starting
point in terms of results we evalu on V
Arena you so that um model based
planning is more accurate than reactive
planning and slightly Trails three
search but remember Tre search is only
possible because we are working in a
sandbox environment which is real web
Arena uh if it's on the real websites
then backtracking in research will
become hard and also the modelbased
planning is much cheaper and much
faster okay so the take aways for
planning I think langage agents are
expanding into this new planning
scenarios categorized by the expressive
but fuzzy goal specifications the
open-ended action spaces and the more
difficult go tests um but the language
for reasoning enables new capabilities
planning abilities like the world models
model basic planning and what we we
didn't talk about today but the
hierarchical planning and dynamic
replanning is also very
important um and the best planning
strategy is dependent on the lrm if you
have a stronger based LM that it may
require less scaffolding so you can your
planning strategy could be more
reactive um but generally how to improv
planning in L is still largely an open
question it's I think many people are
trying the recipe for o style reasoning
um try to see whether that works for
planning but that's still a big open
question okay so I think we're really
just standing at the dawn of a long
journey um we talked about planning
reasoning World models and memory uh but
there are a lot of other things we
didn't talk about and there's a lot to
be done
um just a few immediate future
directions uh I find interesting think
uh memory personalization and continue
learning we're really just scratching
the surface there is a whole lot to be
done how to enable agent to continue the
learn from use and
exploration um the reasoning like how to
uh make o1 or R1 style reing work for
language agents where you need to deal
with this fuz the world without reliable
rewards and how to integrate these
external actions and environmental
States and that's a big open question
and I expect there will be a lot of
study on this in
2025 then planning how to build better
World models instead of just like
simulator one and how how to balance the
reactive and model based planning
because they don't really want to do
simulation at every single step that's
very costly even though humans can do
simulation we don't do that every single
for every single decision right only for
those difficult ones but how to balance
this reactive and model based planning
is a still an open question um how to
sustain a long Horizon then for safety I
think that's a very pressing issue that
keeps me really keeps me up at night um
I think the attack surface of language
agents is scarily Brad right for web
agents the tax surface is essentially
the entire internet like some can ined
something on a a Sim benign website and
you're like for example open AI deep
research agent can go there visit there
and get tricked by it and then maybe
release your reveal your private
information and so and things like that
so there are two general types of safety
issues there's the endogenous risk so
these are the safety risks originat from
within from the agent itself usually
because of the incompetency of the agent
so you can mistakenly take some
irreversible actions that do harm and
then there there are exogenous risks
right so this the risk from the Eastern
environments okay so but there are also
a lot of exciting applications uh the
probably the the um the one with the
most clear business case is atic search
or deep research if you have not use
like clex Pro or Google open deep
research I highly encourage you to try
that and I think something big is being
uh uh baked here um I think this will
become a huge thing in
2025 then also like workflow a
Automation and personally I'm very
excited about uh developing agents for
Sciences um these are all very
exciting so for more um uh a more
comprehensive coverage on language agent
I encourage you to check out our
tutorial with de and we just did at MLP
like two months ago and all the
materials like slides and uh videos are
available on our
website U I thank all of my sponsors and
be happy to take any questions